<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Emilie Yu - Personal site</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Emilie Yu - Personal site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:26:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://em-yu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CASSIE: Curve And Surface Sketching in Immersive Environments</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/cassie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/cassie/</guid><description>We prototype a 3D sketching interface in VR, where the user&amp;rsquo;s strokes are automatically neatened to form a well-connected curve network. We additionnaly infer and create surface patches on the sketch, making it possible to create a 3D surface from a few 3D brush strokes.</description></item><item><title>MSc Thesis: Interactive 3D Sketching in Virtual Reality</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/msc-thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 18:56:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/msc-thesis/</guid><description>During my MSc thesis at DTU supervised by &lt;a href="http://people.compute.dtu.dk/janba/">Andreas Bærentzen&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www-sop.inria.fr/members/Adrien.Bousseau/">Adrien Bousseau&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://tiborstanko.sk/">Tibor Stanko&lt;/a>, I implemented a VR sketching application in Unity and experimented with automatic neatening of strokes, formation of curve networks from the strokes, and infering surface patches. We finally conducted a small remote user study. This work was the basis for our next paper, CASSIE.</description></item><item><title>Simulation of Differential Growth</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/project/simulation-of-differential-growth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 19:49:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/project/simulation-of-differential-growth/</guid><description>Inspired by awesome generative artists such as &lt;a href="https://n-e-r-v-o-u-s.com/">Nervous System&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://inconvergent.net/">inconvergent&lt;/a>, I built a web application simulating the penomenon of differential growth on a surface. My goal was to build an interactive tool to grow organic looking surfaces. The outcome of this project was this live demo in the browser (you can try it) and some 3D prints!</description></item><item><title>Voxel Editor</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/project/voxel-editor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 20:10:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/project/voxel-editor/</guid><description>For the final project of DTU course 02561 Computer graphics, we set out to build a simple voxel editor. This is a Javascript/WebGL project, with a pretty barebone UI. My favorite part was working on the picking interaction for creation and deletion of voxels.</description></item><item><title>Music and travel videos - Globeshakers Project</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/project/videos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 17:57:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/project/videos/</guid><description>I was very lucky to embark on a 6 months trip with a group of friends, during which we travelled the world and played music in the streets and bars, as a brassband. I was the reporter of the team, so I documented those precious moments, directed video clips and edited all of that into some videos.</description></item></channel></rss>