<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on Emilie Yu</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on Emilie Yu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:26:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://em-yu.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>texTile: Making and Re-making Crochet Granny Square Garments Through Computational Design and 3D-printed Connectors</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/textile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/textile/</guid><description>We developed texTile, a modular fashion workflow that enables designers to assemble reusable crochet tiles into garments. To support our workflow, we developed digitally fabricated connectors for easy assembly and disassembly, a custom pattern solver and user interface to guide garment design, and a visualization tool to help plan manual assembly and reassembly.</description></item><item><title>3D-Layers: Bringing Layer-Based Color Editing to VR Painting</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/3dlayers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/3dlayers/</guid><description>VR artists create beautiful 3D paintings with colored 3D brushstrokes. We investigate how the paradigm of ``painting layers&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; could translate to the 3D painting space to achieve non-destructive color editing effects.</description></item><item><title>PhD Thesis: Designing Tools for 3D Content Authoring Based on 3D Sketching</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/phd-tesis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 18:56:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/phd-tesis/</guid><description>3D strokes: what are they? what can we use them for?</description></item><item><title>VideoDoodles: Hand-Drawn Animations on Videos with Scene-Aware Canvases</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/videodoodles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 14:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/videodoodles/</guid><description>We study how artists create VideoDoodles (mix of video and hand-drawn animation) and propose a novel user interface to simplify this task based on depth and motion priors.</description></item><item><title>Piecewise-Smooth Surface Fitting onto Unstructured 3D Sketches</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/surfacing_3d_sketches/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 14:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/surfacing_3d_sketches/</guid><description>We propose a method to transform unstructured 3D sketches into piecewise smooth surfaces that preserve sketched geometric features.</description></item><item><title>CASSIE: Curve And Surface Sketching in Immersive Environments</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/cassie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:26:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/cassie/</guid><description>We prototype a 3D sketching interface in VR, where the user&amp;rsquo;s strokes are automatically neatened to form a well-connected curve network. We additionnaly infer and create surface patches on the sketch, making it possible to create a 3D surface from a few 3D brush strokes.</description></item><item><title>MSc Thesis: Interactive 3D Sketching in Virtual Reality</title><link>https://em-yu.github.io/research/msc-thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 18:56:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://em-yu.github.io/research/msc-thesis/</guid><description>During my MSc thesis at DTU supervised by &lt;a href="http://people.compute.dtu.dk/janba/">Andreas Bærentzen&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www-sop.inria.fr/members/Adrien.Bousseau/">Adrien Bousseau&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://tiborstanko.sk/">Tibor Stanko&lt;/a>, I implemented a VR sketching application in Unity and experimented with automatic neatening of strokes, formation of curve networks from the strokes, and infering surface patches. We finally conducted a small remote user study. This work was the basis for our next paper, CASSIE.</description></item></channel></rss>